Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Hello.
Kostadis Roussos: Hello.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Hello, co-starvis. How are you?
Kostadis Roussos: Everything's good. I was testing out the audio setup.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Mmm…
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: I think I just started my Discord, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: That's fine.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Okay, yes, I'm online.
Kostadis Roussos: I'm trying to see…
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: some messages… Thank you. Oh, yes, yes, sorry.
Kostadis Roussos: Awesome.
Kostadis Roussos: I don't… I actually didn't know which one you were gonna use.
Kostadis Roussos: So I sent you messages on all three.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Oh, yes, yes, yes, thanks for that. My desktop Discord client, I did not check.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Okay, so…
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, there's a bit.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: of the Stonehill Inn.
Kostadis Roussos: Awesome.
Kostadis Roussos: Huh.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: The storyline is pretty interesting, Costa. That's why I've just been, like, waiting to play it again.
Kostadis Roussos: Excellent.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: I've been bugging you, bugging you, like, a couple of times.
Kostadis Roussos: No, dude, I'm enjoying it, too.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Oh, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: If I wasn't… trust me, I don't play things I don't find interesting.
Kostadis Roussos: Sure. Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Fuck.
Kostadis Roussos: I'm a French student.
Kostadis Roussos: Nope.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so when we last left our noble adventurers.
Kostadis Roussos: They had just entered, the Stonehill Tavern.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes. They were planning to spend the night before they headed off to,
Kostadis Roussos: To go… to go fight, to go, to go rescue their patron, gunther.
Kostadis Roussos: Gunthar.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes. Who, everybody hopes is still alive.
Kostadis Roussos: Of course, he might not be, in which case it's kind of sad, and, you know, your decision to come and spend the night at the tavern may cost him his life, but, you know…
Kostadis Roussos: Such is the brakes.
Kostadis Roussos: You know, such as… such are the choices of adventurers.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Playing God, playing God, you know, kind of thing.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Okay, stays alone.
Kostadis Roussos: Hopefully he's still alive. Alright. So…
Kostadis Roussos: No, let me just get rid of this one.
Kostadis Roussos: Delete.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, I need to do… Excellent.
Kostadis Roussos: It's been gone.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so you are in the Stonehill Tavern.
Kostadis Roussos: In.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, let's, place the party.
Kostadis Roussos: You can see it, I hope.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Yes, I can see it inside the taverns.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so… Alright, so you're in the Stonehill… that seems a bit… about the same rate size. Alright. Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Pretty big tavern. Okay, so this is the Stonehill Tavern, and who else… who is in the Stonehill Tavern? The area behind, you know, so this is the main tavern area. The thing on the left that you could see is the second floor.
Kostadis Roussos: Right, the other half of the map?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, this is the second floor.
Kostadis Roussos: Did you mark something? I can… So, no, I'm just… I just did it now.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Hold a second.
Kostadis Roussos: Can you see it?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: No, I don't see any mark.
Kostadis Roussos: I see… you should see… what map are you looking at? What do you see on the map right now?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Okay, hold on, let me share my screen.
Kostadis Roussos: You're not zooming out.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: I did sue out.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, I just, okay, zoom out all the way.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so, here, let me share.
Kostadis Roussos: Joe, share, share your screen.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Okay.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: This is what I'm seeing.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, scroll to the right.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Oh, oh, all the way, okay.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: That's black.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, that's the second floor.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: I heard, okay, cool, yes, okay. So all I could see was this.
Kostadis Roussos: So you can see the first floor. Alright, now let me just drop the characters, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Oops.
Kostadis Roussos: So there's a commoner.
Kostadis Roussos: October.
Kostadis Roussos: Still in the dark.
Kostadis Roussos: works.
Kostadis Roussos: So, I'm gonna drop the NPCs you can interact with.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Toblin Stonehill owner, okay.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: A few people at the farm.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright…
Kostadis Roussos: Oops.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Alrighty.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: So, the place, it's in the middle of the day, so it's, you know, there's not many people here today.
Kostadis Roussos: Such a large place, it's kind of confusing that there aren't that many people here. But so be it.
Kostadis Roussos: And… let me just read this.
Kostadis Roussos: The opening… the common room is warm but watchful. Everyone has heared a wagon come in without Gundren. A few local pretend not to stare. Others are waiting to see whether you are brave, dangerous, or merely passing through.
Kostadis Roussos: Toblin approaches you with some forced hospitality. Rooms are ready, hot stew if you want it, and if you're Goodrin's friends, well, folk here, we all want to know what you know.
Kostadis Roussos: He's a broad-shouldered, young human man with sandy hair, tired blue eyes, and rolled-up sleeves, dusted with flour and hearth hash.
Kostadis Roussos: He smiles easily, but keeps glancing to the door whenever voices rise.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: So
Kostadis Roussos: you can sort of ask them about rumors, stories, I mean, it's up to you, or you can, like, sit down…
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: The person who approached is the tuck, or…
Kostadis Roussos: It's, Toblin, sorry, I should have, yeah, let me just make sure.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, I was… I forgot to keep forgetting. If you don't mind, stop sharing, because I keep thinking I'm looking at…
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Okay.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Okay, that's perfect.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright. So, right.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: No problem. Okay. Well, thank you for having us tonight.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: tell us more about how, Gundrin was, like, what were…
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: What were his, like, times of visit, or, you know…
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: How was he related to you?
Kostadis Roussos: Well, he's not related to me, but, you know, he brought business, he was a merchant, he was a good man.
Kostadis Roussos: And his brother did good business here, so, you know, and losing somebody is always… we always, you know, we always, what, care about our people.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Well, yeah, let's not make any assumptions. We still have not lost him. I'm gonna bring him back.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, well, that's, that's wonderful to hear. I, I, that's, that is… that is…
Kostadis Roussos: That is wonderful to hear.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: So, were there any threats for him that you knew of?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Do you have any enemies that you know? Was he involved in any fights here?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: I asked too many questions at the same.
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, that's fine, you're fine, like, I just need to figure out… okay, so, ask your question?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Hmm.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Did he have any enemies, or was he involved in any fights here before?
Kostadis Roussos: Toblin says, look.
Kostadis Roussos: I don't like trouble, and I don't want trouble, so why don't you grab a table, and Elsa will come and feed you.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay. Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: So, grab a table. Yeah, he goes, like, you know, this… he pauses and turns to you and says, what does he say?
Kostadis Roussos: He says, hold on, hold on, he says.
Kostadis Roussos: I don't like trouble in my common room. Trumbull and Phandalin has a habit of walking home with you.
Kostadis Roussos: So you get the impression that he's the kind of guy who's, like, he's… he's… you definitely get a vibe that there's some… that there is trouble in Vandalin.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Right? Right. And he doesn't, he doesn't want to, he, so he goes
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah. Right? Elsa comes out, says, and says, shouts, grab a table, or pick a stool on the bar. So where would you like to go?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: I would go to the bar table, because that's where I feel most conversations might happen.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so you're gonna go to the bar, alright?
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: She's a dwarf bartender, sharp-eyed.
Kostadis Roussos: She's a compact dwarf woman with copper-brown skin, thick black braids pinned beneath a hat kerchief, and four arms strung from hauling casks. Her dark eyes miss nothing, and she polishes mugs like she's interrogating them.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Okay? Oh, yeah, so I'll ask her, like, to get her something to drink.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, she says, well, that is very kind of you.
Kostadis Roussos: That is very, very kind of you.
Kostadis Roussos: And let me just do something here.
Kostadis Roussos: That is very kind of you, and she pours a beer and pours you a beer.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, and so she goes, are you from,
Kostadis Roussos: Are you from Fan… did you guys just come in from… you guys just came in from Fangolin, right?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Yes, yeah, this is Fandland, but we…
Kostadis Roussos: No, sorry, Neverwinter, Neverwinter, sorry, I meant to say. She goes, well, well, well, my sister, my sister is a scholar in the city of Neverwinter, and she, and you can see she's very, very proud of it. Vera recognizes the name.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Oh, do you know her sister, Vera?
Kostadis Roussos: Vera says, No… But, I think my mentor, Professor Oren Voss, knew her.
Kostadis Roussos: So that's his name.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Do you… But you said your professor disappeared here, right?
Kostadis Roussos: She goes…
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, well, he came to Phandalin shortly before vanishing. He believed that there were black stone fragments that were part of some large obelisk.
Kostadis Roussos: You see this blue candle? It reacted to obelisk fragments and certain kinds of psionic magic. He feared the obelisk was connected to minds, memory, and transformation.
Kostadis Roussos: And what he told me was, never let anyone assemble the fragments… fragments.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay. So, what to make of that information, but I'm thinking…
Kostadis Roussos: I mean, but part of it, so as you're looking, you kind of, like, absorb this information, right?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Yes, yes.
Kostadis Roussos: She goes, I just want to know that he wasn't losing his mind.
Kostadis Roussos: I mean, it sounds so crazy, doesn't it?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: It does, does, yes.
Kostadis Roussos: He was such a… he was such a good man, and I don't want… it has to not be that he was losing his mind.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: We are on our way to Fandelin something.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Similar happened to me when we hit a rock.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: I noticed, like, I believe I saw a shadow of an obelisk or something.
Kostadis Roussos: So you say that, right, out loud?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: say that. I say that out to Vera.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, let me say that's a Vera.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Yeah, yeah, I mean, others who are at the bar table then, so…
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: pip… What's poop, poop says.
Kostadis Roussos: I was… Let's see, where is it now?
Kostadis Roussos: Pip says…
Kostadis Roussos: Iraz, looking for something, yeah, looking for some notes.
Kostadis Roussos: Pip says, I heard a whisper that said, returned.
Kostadis Roussos: Right?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: And Mela says, really? Because I felt a brief chill in my holy symbol.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Like, right now?
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, no, no, when the…
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Oh, okay, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: I, I just thought I was going crazy.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Oh, hmm. So, something is strange here, then.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: I also don't hear of any insurance like this before.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: I'm gonna inscribe.
Kostadis Roussos: You're asking, you're asking, Elsa, right?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: So, yes.
Kostadis Roussos: She goes, She turns to Vera and Hugh and says, you know, she looks at Vera and says.
Kostadis Roussos: you're not the first bookish sort to come here looking for old… at old stones, and yes, I've seen many people. In fact, my sister is… my sister goes off and explains how her sister is this really important person who's… and that she's very proud of her, and that she… she became, you know, the pride of the family.
Kostadis Roussos: Right?
Kostadis Roussos: She also says, you know, Darren Elder Edtermath, the orchard keeper, is a former adventurer.
Kostadis Roussos: He might have more information about this place.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Interesting. Where is he? What does he do?
Kostadis Roussos: What, where is he?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Where can I find Darren?
Kostadis Roussos: And, I will show you on the adventure map.
Kostadis Roussos: You will find him…
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so the orchard is here.
Kostadis Roussos: Here being, I can see it on my map, but you can't see it on yours.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: down green, shrine of luck.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Don't have time.
Kostadis Roussos: Can you see it? Endermath Orchard.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Trying to find… Yes, yes, I did a math, either math, watch it, yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Eatermath Orchard. Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: She goes, well, if you're interested in adventure, he might, he might know something, but, you know, if you ask me,
Kostadis Roussos: You know, I think you should just wait for my sister, and she'll figure everything out, because she's that kind of person.
Kostadis Roussos: She's really smart, you know? She got and proceeds to explain how she got accepted to the right universities, and the right scholars, and is all the rage of the family. You can tell that she's very proud of her sister.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: It seems like you're proud of your sister, I'm sure she is, good person and a scholar.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, yes she is.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Okay, then I'm gonna just stand up and…
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, wait, hold on, he goes, hold on, before he goes there, she goes, Darren Edtermeth is in a retired drow adventurer.
Kostadis Roussos: He's, like, over 500 years old, and has worked as a marshal and herald for many years in the lands of the Dragon Coast, far to the south.
Kostadis Roussos: He's a… he's a good guy that you should go talk to.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Good enough.
Kostadis Roussos: And, he's heard stories, from all over, and if there's anything that you want to know about this place, I'm sure he knows about it.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Nope.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Thank you also for the information, I…
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: You seem like a nice person.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, she goes, of course I'm a nice person, and you're a nice person for buying me a beer.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Thank you.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: then I'm gonna… Stand up and, you know, lift my glass and say cheers, just to get attention of…
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: The peop… other people on the… in the bar?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: I see there are some other NPCs who I still have not interacted, so…
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Yeah. So, yeah, that's what I would do, and then…
Kostadis Roussos: So, so you, Frida looks at you very nervously and quietly, and angry, but not at you, but angry about something.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Sweet, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: So, she's a gnomish… you look at her, and she's a single, slight gnomish woman with all silver-streaked hair, round spectacles, and a shawl of her own careful weaving. Her fingers are always moving, twisting loose thread, or, whirring at the edge of her sleeves.
Kostadis Roussos: She turns to you and says, are you new here?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Yes, ma'am.
Kostadis Roussos: goes… Jose says, well, sit down.
Kostadis Roussos: And she orders… she barks like a matronly mother to have you sit down, so I presume you grab chairs and sit down?
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: I'm assuming, like, you can tell me you don't.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Yeah, we do sit down, yes.
Kostadis Roussos: You do sit down. Alright. Okay…
Kostadis Roussos: So, Freda says, I don't know what, you know, I, you know, I, I heard you said that Gunthar was, was missing.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, you know, I know who's behind it.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Oh, that's interesting. Can you tell us, please?
Kostadis Roussos: The Red Brands. They're a gang of… it's a grant… the Red Brands.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Red branch.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Kostadis Roussos: I want them gone.
Kostadis Roussos: But, I don't want my neighbors to get hurt.
Kostadis Roussos: And here she goes.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: What does the neighbors have to do with this here?
Kostadis Roussos: She goes, well, I mean, I want them gone, but I don't want any of my neighbors hurt.
Kostadis Roussos: And she's looking at you like, you're not neighbors. Therefore, if you were to get them gone and get herd, that would satisfy her two constraints. Her goal, and her constraint.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: That is selfish, but okay.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: No, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, yes, she says.
Kostadis Roussos: You know, she's got… she's got this small voice, but, like, this big resentment. And then she goes, you know what I noticed about the red brands?
Kostadis Roussos: They bother everyone. Everyone except Halia. Makes you wonder whether they fear her, owe her, or both.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Who is Halia here?
Kostadis Roussos: Halia? Oh, she goes, who's Halia?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Yep.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, let me, let me just give you that information.
Kostadis Roussos: Halia… She explains… Oh, goodness.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, bye.
Kostadis Roussos: Come on, how are you?
Kostadis Roussos: Huh.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: She works… she works at the Fandelin Miners Exchange.
Kostadis Roussos: So, let me just, make… so Holly, apparently, he goes… she turns to you and says, if you're the kind of person who wants to find out who's a crook and who's a criminal, and who's behind it all, I'd start there.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so the Phandalin Miner Exchange.
Kostadis Roussos: Why knows it's in…
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Do you want to go talk to the other two people?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Yes, yes, I wanna pretend…
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: To be drunk a little bit, and then try to make a small talk with the other two people, and…
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: The, the…
Kostadis Roussos: Stonehill, stuck Stonehill, as well.
Kostadis Roussos: Pardon me?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Stonehill, the son of the owner, Oh.
Kostadis Roussos: You wanna go talk to him?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Yeah, I've not spoken to these three people, so…
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, well, Tuck is a 9-year-old boy, and he kind of approaches you.
Kostadis Roussos: He's got a mop of sandy hair, a missing front tooth, and knees scuffed from climbing things he was told not to climb. He tries to stand like a guard when watching.
Kostadis Roussos: He goes… Oh!
Kostadis Roussos: K, I wanna tell you something.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Right. What's up, little kid?
Kostadis Roussos: He said, Kerp saw a tunnel, a real one, but his ma said to not talk about it because the red cloaks nearly caught him.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Wait, who saw the tunnel?
Kostadis Roussos: He goes, Kerp, my friend!
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Oh, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Carp. Carp at… you know Karp.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Nope.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, Carp, Carp is… Carp Alderleaf, he, his ma, he's my good friend, and he said he saw a tunnel that goes into the woods, and that, you know, but his ma said to not go there, because that's where the red cloaks are.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Do you know where the tunnel is?
Kostadis Roussos: He goes, oh yeah, I can totally show you! And you don't know if he can, or he's gonna get his friend to show it, but yes, you could get him to show it to you.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: This… Okay, we can do that sometime. Thanks for that. Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: He goes, and he goes…
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: No kicking.
Kostadis Roussos: You know, he then pauses to you, says,
Kostadis Roussos: You know, you're going after Gundren, right?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Good.
Kostadis Roussos: People who get taken don't always come back.
Kostadis Roussos: You're gonna get him, right?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Yes. Has anyone else got taken before? Like… Conrun?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: many people.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: -Oh.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: That's sad.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: You're gonna get me back.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so the next person is North.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Not, yes.
Kostadis Roussos: He's an older human man with weathered skin, a stooped back, and pale eyes that linger on windows, doorways, and bad omens. He smells faintly of hay, rain, and pipe smoke.
Kostadis Roussos: He looks at, he looks at you and goes.
Kostadis Roussos: He looks at Sister Mela, and says, You're temple folk, aren't you?
Kostadis Roussos: Sister Mela says, yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Ugh, well, Sister Garil came back limping and pale. Wouldn't say from where.
Kostadis Roussos: Folks who serve gods learn when not to speak, I suppose. Then he pauses.
Kostadis Roussos: Maybe she'll talk to you before she talks to the rest of us.
Kostadis Roussos: I'm kind of worried about her, and it would be really kind if you were to go talk to her. She won't talk to us, because she's always trying to protect us, but maybe you can go find out what's going on?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Yeah, yeah, I can definitely find out if he's willing to talk to me, I can give it a try.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Thank you for that.
Kostadis Roussos: M…
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: And, okay, yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: And then, and then, Laenar sort of stands up, and goes.
Kostadis Roussos: You notice he's a lean human with sunken cheeks, a dusty gray beard, and cracked hands permanently stained by ore and lamp suit. His cap sits crooked, and he talks with a mug lifted halfway to his mouth.
Kostadis Roussos: He speaks loudly, right? And he goes…
Kostadis Roussos: Everybody here doesn't really want to talk about the issues. Goblins, bandits, orcs, Redbander. Red brand, doesn't matter what they use. Roads aren't safe, and Harbor and Wester is still hiding behind notices and wax seals.
Kostadis Roussos: You want to ask, who's Harbin Wester?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Who's Harbin Western?
Kostadis Roussos: He is the Town Master!
Kostadis Roussos: Useless… he is the town master. Oh my god, is he useless.
Kostadis Roussos: He's like, he's done nothing! He has done nothing. Well, and thank God you folks have come here! Pauses and says, if you ask me all the… we… somebody has to deal with why the roads aren't safe. I mean, poor Guntherin was captured, and you were at… were you attacked? Were you attacked?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: No, yes, yes, we were attacked, yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Why are you testing?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: We were attacked by the goblin.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Way to the family.
Kostadis Roussos: Wait, why are you going Hindi?
Kostadis Roussos: Wait, hold on, my… Everybody died, TPK, all new characters. My wife's saying everybody died, TPK.
Kostadis Roussos: There's only one person! Yeah, it's a coworker of mine. That's not D&D! Yes, it is.
Kostadis Roussos: His character died, rolling. Alright, so, do you want a bear? I'd love one, yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so the only thing that you might want to do is, like,
Kostadis Roussos: Go back to Toblin and ask him about the red brands.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Hold on, wait a second.
Kostadis Roussos: The, the, the, the, the, the, the, the guy…
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: He's at the table, back at the table, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Right, not Toblin, you know, he's the, the owner of the place, right?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Sorry, Toblin is… sort of… Toblin's over here.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Well, Lynn was at the bar, yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, right. So…
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: I will go by.
Kostadis Roussos: Texas.
Kostadis Roussos: You go back to him?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes. Thank you. Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Do you want to ask him, like… you now have learned, like, you know, there's apparently these red brands, there's goblins, there's the mayor, there's a cleric that was wounded, like…
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Yeah, I'm gonna ask him, hey, Toblin,
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: I've been hearing about the red, brands.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: And… decks, on the road, and both the town master and Darren.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: What's going on? It looks like everything is weird in this town, like, can you care to tell me? Might help us in finding Gundrin, safe and sound.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, look…
Kostadis Roussos: Red Brands killed a man in the street, broad daylight. Then his wife and children vanished, so forgive me if I lower my voice.
Kostadis Roussos: Pauses. They drink at the sleeping… they drink at the.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Go elsewhere and talk if you want. You're… you don't feel safe talking in the hallway.
Kostadis Roussos: No, he goes, he turns around, these are all friends, but I don't want to talk too loudly.
Kostadis Roussos: And he goes.
Kostadis Roussos: So… so he said… but he does tell you that the… he tells you the name of the person who was murdered.
Kostadis Roussos: Tell Dendar.
Kostadis Roussos: And that they… the red brands drink at the sleeping giants.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: What? The red brands drink at the sleeping gym?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Okay.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: What's a sleeping giant, that's it.
Kostadis Roussos: That's a look… yes, and so he shows you… he tells you where it is, so let me just show you where it is on the map.
Kostadis Roussos: The sleeping giant.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, can you see it?
Kostadis Roussos: He's a living giant.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Awesome.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Pretty much they are in the town, like, almost outside of the town, a little bit.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, I mean, this is a small town, right? And so this distance here is, like…
Kostadis Roussos: I don't know, 250… 200 feet?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Right, right, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: So, Sleeping Giant is… you can ask him about the Sleeping Giant.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: So, are the red brands, like, bandits?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Or are they, like, you know, do they have any menagical powers?
Kostadis Roussos: Do they have it? He goes… he goes, they're just tough guys.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: They're just tough guys who've managed to come into our small town and to think that they run the place.
Kostadis Roussos: And nobody has stood up to them.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Interesting. Why hasn't Darren stepped up? He seems to… I heard that he seems to be an adventurer.
Kostadis Roussos: And he turns and says, well, you may not know this, but most adventurers die.
Kostadis Roussos: And the only ones that live are the ones that quit while they're ahead.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Okay.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Makes sense.
Kostadis Roussos: Not everybody is… not everybody is… most adventurers either die or quit.
Kostadis Roussos: You tell me.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Tell me a little more about the sleeping giant, like, what was it? Is it, like, an inn, or have they occupied…
Kostadis Roussos: Just like that, huh?
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so, great question.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so this is a rundown tap house. It's a dirty… it's a dirty, dangerous watering hole at the end of Fandland's Main Street.
Kostadis Roussos: It is… is frequent… and he goes, that's where the red brands hang out.
Kostadis Roussos: Now, as you're pausing here, you realize this is a frontier town, right?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Yep.
Kostadis Roussos: And so one of the…
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: What you're done, sorry.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, yes. You're from India, why would you know that? Okay, so… Ethnic… So, in…
Kostadis Roussos: A common trope in Dungeons & Dragons is the idea of a town
Kostadis Roussos: That is at the edge of civilization.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Oh, I see, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: And so towns that are at the edge of civilization are kind of like… have you seen Star Wars?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Yes, yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Moss Isley.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: I don't remember, but…
Kostadis Roussos: That's where Luke Skywalker tries… says where Obi-Wan Kenobi says, sky of it, villainy?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Oh, I still don't recall, but yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: That's fine.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: It's like a… it's like a… what do you say? Almost beaten-down town kind of thing, right?
Kostadis Roussos: Well, it's not beaten down, but it's kind of like the central authorities don't have much power. How about I put it that way?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Okay, okay,
Kostadis Roussos: Right, so I don't know, like, I'm sure in India there are towns where the central authorities have left them… left the towns to fend for themselves.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Right? And in those towns, as you could imagine, the criminal element thrives.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Yes, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Right? And so, that's the way to think about the red breads.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Okay, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: This is a town which is at the limits of the central government's power.
Kostadis Roussos: And… As a result, gangs emerge.
Kostadis Roussos: And what you've clearly gathered is the Red Brands are one of those gangs.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Right, yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Right? And this is kind of normal, like, as someone who… you would expect this kind of thing, like, for all you know, they're just a bunch of people, like, you don't know why they killed… who they killed. Maybe that guy pissed them off, maybe that guy was a member of the gang. My point is, you don't actually know who or what they are, you just know that some people don't like this gang.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Right, okay, okay.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Yeah, I get a sense of it, like, Vegas was once upon a time, like,
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: You know, dictated by the gangsters.
Kostadis Roussos: Right. So, if you think of it that way.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Does that make sense?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Yes, got it.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so yeah, so it's, it's… that's the way to think about it. Alright. And so, you know, night to… so then, that's it for today, you wake up in the morning, and I presume you're gonna head up back to go find out what the heck happened to Gunther?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Yeah, so.
Kostadis Roussos: Or you want to go talk to. Holly Arrow, what do you want to do?
Kostadis Roussos: Don't forget…
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Yeah, before…
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, let's go. Yeah, so what do you… what it's… what do you want to do? Do you want to, like, this morning…
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: So you're saying, like, every minute I spend in this town is gonna cost his life?
Kostadis Roussos: That's what people are telling you.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: But I do need some information, right? So I wanted to talk to Darren, I wanted to talk to Halia.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so you wanna go talk to Darren?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Yeah, real quick, like, you know, maybe 1 hour or two hours before I start.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, you know, if… who knows, maybe you'll learn something useful, right?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Yes.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Information is found.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: So,
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so, he, he, you, you see him, he's, Darren is well over 500 or 500 years old, he's worked as a marshal and herald for many years in the lands of the Dragon Coast, part of the South.
Kostadis Roussos: Upon returning, he returned to Neverwinter, the region his original home, right?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Wait, he's 500 years old?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, they're elves, they live that long.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: So let me just get… I need to get a commoner…
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: He's,
Kostadis Roussos: He definitely has that look of somebody who's seen it all, done it all, but is very happy to see you. He goes.
Kostadis Roussos: When he sees you, he goes, Why? Are you… are you adventurers?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Meh… Not exactly, but we fall in that category.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, elf.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Maybe then Pip might step in and try to show off.
Kostadis Roussos: Pip goes, we are absolutely adventurers. He stands. I, I, I, and he proceeds to explain how I came to Fandelin because I believe that it's important for us to do good, and because I know there's always somebody, there's always a community that needs a man who's got a good sword arm.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay. Right.
Kostadis Roussos: Darren looks at him and says, Pip, you are my kind of man.
Kostadis Roussos: Pip, like, smiles profusely. Like, obviously the guy's got issues where…
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Nice, yes.
Kostadis Roussos: He's being… he's being recognized. He's like, I'm… I'm… And he goes…
Kostadis Roussos: He goes, well, I gotta tell you something, Pip. I am very concerned about those red brands, and I'd like to see a group of heroes just like you guys teach those ruffians a lesson.
Kostadis Roussos: I mean, someone's gotta take… take a stand against their leader.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Yeah, so what happened? Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: needs to take a stand. That's what I said, someone that hasn't taken a stand.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Oh, or needs to take a stand, okay. Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: His name's Glass Staff.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Last time.
Kostadis Roussos: You're at Glassdeaf.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: faster. Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Out of here.
Kostadis Roussos: One word. He goes, anyway…
Kostadis Roussos: The red brands, let me just tell you some things I've learned. I keep an eye out on things. I was once a marshal, so I know how to keep track of criminals and ruffians.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: That's interesting. Skill. Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: He goes,
Kostadis Roussos: The red brands hang around the sleeping giant tap house, but I do know where their safe house is.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Where is it?
Kostadis Roussos: It's under Tresander Manor.
Kostadis Roussos: You should see it over here.
Kostadis Roussos: You see it? It's past the sleeping giant?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Yes, yes.
Kostadis Roussos: You see this orange-yellow dot here?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Yes, rundowned house.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: He goes, that's where their safe house is.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: What's it called?
Kostadis Roussos: Tressenderer Manor.
Kostadis Roussos: No.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright?
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Okay.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Oh, transcender, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Then.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Do you know how many of the red brands are there?
Kostadis Roussos: How many are there? At the Tressender Manor.
Kostadis Roussos: Somewhere between 3 and 10.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: That's a huge range.
Kostadis Roussos: You know, I'm saying I don't know the exact number, so…
Kostadis Roussos: I'm telling you, as Castatas, between 3 and 10, and he would tell you the… he would tell you the exact number. It would take me a while to go figure it out. Does that make sense?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Oh, I see, okay, okay, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Then he pauses and says, Well, Pip… I like you.
Kostadis Roussos: Pip Blake goes, yes?
Kostadis Roussos: And I got a problem that I think you should deal with.
Kostadis Roussos: I've heard that there are prospectors in the hills northwest of Fandland that someone is digging in the ruins known as the Old Owl Well.
Kostadis Roussos: And apparently, several prospectors have been reported being chased from the area by foul undead.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, because you may not know what undead are, undead are goblins… are creatures that have been
Kostadis Roussos: So in Dungeons & Dragons, there are creatures who,
Kostadis Roussos: aren't dead and aren't alive. They've been basically reanimated. So, zombies, vampires, ghouls, ghasts, whites, all of that, alright?
Kostadis Roussos: He goes, now… I need to tell you…
Kostadis Roussos: It's a couple days march northeast of Fandelin, find out who's there and what they're doing.
Kostadis Roussos: Now, I know those ruins are an old watchtower of an ancient magical empire known as Netheril, and I'm worried that there's some dangerous magic that might be there. Now, you can go there and ensure there's no threat to the town brewing at Old Dwell. I'm willing to give you some boots of striding and springing.
Kostadis Roussos: If you… he goes, he goes, it came in handy when I was an adventurer, but,
Kostadis Roussos: But I'm out of the game, so I'd be willing to give them if you were to do such a good turn for the town.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Well, I would do it, but first, I guess we have to go back, find our friend.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, you should. Yes, well, he goes, yes, you should.
Kostadis Roussos: Wait, he pauses and goes, wait, you're talking to me instead of going to go find Gundren? Shame on you, you should go now!
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Oh, okay. That seems to be important. Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Pip goes, I'm sorry, I'm sorry, we just thought we'd get more information. Pip, I'm not gonna hold this against you, but, you know, it's important to get information, and then it's important to do the right thing, and, you know, the right thing is for you to go and find it, and go and rescue Gundrin.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Yes, no, I'm still thinking if I should go talk to Halia, or just to…
Kostadis Roussos: It's up to you, man. It's up to you.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: It's a tough choice, okay.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: The pleasure.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Okay, I'll take a leap of faith, just, pray at the Shrine of luck, and then head to the tribe board train.
Kostadis Roussos: You're gonna go to the Shrine of Luck?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: I'll just, for a minute, pray to the guard, and then head out to the adventure, hoping, you know, the information from Halia is irrelevant.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, let me see… Alrighty.
Kostadis Roussos: Phandalin's only temple, this small shrine is made of stones taken from the nearby ruins. It is dedicated to Tamora, the god of good luck and good fortune.
Kostadis Roussos: The Shrain is in the care of a scholarly acolyte. She's a Zealous young elf.
Kostadis Roussos: Seguerla… Seguerla, she looks at you, Z.
Kostadis Roussos: She… she kind of… It's kind of weird.
Kostadis Roussos: She looks at you and goes, well, I see you're come to pray at the Shrine of Luck.
Kostadis Roussos: And to Tamora.
Kostadis Roussos: And then she looks you over and says, what are you… so, she pauses and says, are you the guys who came in from town where Gunthar was missing?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Yes, we are actually trying to find him.
Kostadis Roussos: oh, well, you know, you should probably… I don't know where he is, but you should go find him. And, you know, may tomorrow's blessing be upon you, and when you find him, and come back, come by, I think I can… I have another job for you.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Okay, sure. Okay, so… Right, okay, so we'll head out.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, she's, you know, she's not…
Kostadis Roussos: She's definitely got the, you definitely get the vibe of, I better not, that she's not gonna give you any more quests until you go and deal…
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Yo.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, until you go and deal with this. Alright, so you head back to where the goblin ambush was.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, and you take, I presume, the Goblin Trail, correct? Yes, yes. The Goblin Trail. Alright.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: As of two humans, right? Right.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright. Alright.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Okay, so one question. In this game, like, there are side quests as well.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, you want to go on the side quests.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: No, I'll finish the main one first. Wait, can we actually go to the side quest once we finish the main one?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, well, okay, so…
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: No, the thing is, like, so…
Kostadis Roussos: So let me tell… so let me explain to you how the game works.
Kostadis Roussos: You have to accumulate experience points, and treasure.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Treasure, as in the coins.
Kostadis Roussos: Horribly. Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: And so, the reason you go on the side quests.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Still get coins.
Kostadis Roussos: Coins and treasure and magic.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: And the other thing you go on the side quest is because a side quest might… you don't actually know what is a main quest and a side quest.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Well, I mean, like, here the main quest is, like, finding and getting back Gundrin.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, that's just… that could be a side… that could be a complete side quest, for all you know.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Oh.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: So, let's suppose if I just jump on a side quest, hypothetically.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Gundam might die.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Okay.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Okay, no, I don't want to kill anyone, so I'll just push forward to this.
Kostadis Roussos: I don't know if it's, like, you know, like, or not.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Yeah, there is a possibility.
Kostadis Roussos: It's… it's just that the reason you might want to go get him is that whoever's got him is trying to get information from him, and at some point in time, they're going to decide they tried enough.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Hmm.
Kostadis Roussos: Does that make sense?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: And once they've decided they've tried enough, they might say, you know, whatever, we're not gonna try this anymore.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Great, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Okie dokie.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so about 10 minutes after heading down the trail,
Kostadis Roussos: Are you searching for traps, or just, like, walking blindly?
Kostadis Roussos: I'm assuming you're search. Now, the downside of search…
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: No, my screen is blank, it's black, black and.
Kostadis Roussos: No, that's fine, that's fine, you're currently walking in the woods.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Oh, okay, so… yeah, we'll be carefully walking, step by step, not rushing through.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so you're, you're kind of like… so here…
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Looking out for, you know, animals, objects, or, you know, some kind of…
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, Pip, who's in the lead?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Let's put Pip, because he seems empowered after talking to Darren.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, pip. Alright, so the one downside of… the one good thing about having pip is Pip is really good at handling ACTACs, but he doesn't have the world's best perception.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Sorry, word?
Kostadis Roussos: Perception. His passive perception isn't very good.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Oh, okay. Well, then I think I should.
Kostadis Roussos: You can walk next to him.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Yeah, I can walk next to him and use my perception.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: What's your passive perception?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: 12.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, Pips is 13. Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay,
Kostadis Roussos: Roll a saving throw, a DC-10… you stumble on a hidden pit. Alright, roll your dexterity saving throw.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Slash dexterity… okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Dexterity saving throw.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, you, You, you avoid falling into the pit.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: You go another 10 minutes…
Kostadis Roussos: And you encounter a hidden snare.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, now Pip needs to roll a DC-10 Dexterity saving throw, so let me see what Pip's saving throw is…
Kostadis Roussos: 630 plus 1…
Kostadis Roussos: Pip is caught up in the snare.
Kostadis Roussos: And he's suspend… he's flip tight, tied down, and suspended 10 feet above the ground.
Kostadis Roussos: I presume one of you's gonna try to lower him?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Yes, yes, I think,
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Sister Mela should lower him, or should I?
Kostadis Roussos: Well, both of you can.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Okay, I'll, lower him first, and then… what do I roll for that?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, you just rolled over him, there's nothing to roll. Alright.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: I don't roll anything?
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, no. Not in this case.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Hmm…
Kostadis Roussos: I also, made sure to have you… you should be able to now see where the, old Owl is, which is the quest you were going on.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Kostadis Roussos: May see it over here.
Kostadis Roussos: Right? You saw that?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: I see a blue… oh yeah, okay, Oldwell, yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Right. Okay.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Where you're going.
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, you're going… you're going towards… you're following this, this trail north.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: After managing to avoid one of the two traps.
Kostadis Roussos: Alrighty, we will go to the map.
Kostadis Roussos: Oops, that's not on…
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Isn't that weird?
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, hold on.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: So, you, the path leads you to…
Kostadis Roussos: The Goblin's Trail ends at a cave in a hillside 5 miles from the scene of the ambush.
Kostadis Roussos: A shallow stream flows from the cave mouth, which is screened by a dense briar and thickets. A narrow, dry path leads onto the cave on the right side of the stream.
Kostadis Roussos: Right, so, so this is the,
Kostadis Roussos: I'm just gonna draw it here, this is the… see the blue line?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, that's the, that's the narrow path, right.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: So…
Kostadis Roussos: Now, are you gonna just sort of… how do you… do you guys want to look around, or do you want to just charge in boldly? What do you guys want to do?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Try to peek around, the narrow path to see.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so who's gonna do… Xenobon, you're the one with, the very high dexterity, the very high stealth, so you probably should do the peaking.
Kostadis Roussos: You go… go pee.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: I'm doing the peaking, and what do I roll?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: And dexterity?
Kostadis Roussos: There's Stealth. Roll the D20, and you should see a stealth? Click on that.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Wait a minute…
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Still, yes, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: What'd you roll?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Yeah. Yay.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: So, you come over there, and you see two goblins, and what else do you see?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Hmm.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: I see 3.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, two goblins and one goblin boss.
Kostadis Roussos: On the east side of the stream that flows from the cave mouth, a small area of briar thickets has been hollowed out to form a lookout post. Wooden plants flatten the briars and provide rooms for guards to be hidden and watch the area, including several goblins lurking there. Right now.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: So… Are my options.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, your options are to go back and tell your party that there's a… there's a… they need to stage an ambush.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Right, okay, okay, yes.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: I was just thinking, if I should start the fight, but it would be foolish. Okay, so I'll go back.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, you go back, and you tell everybody what you saw?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Yes, I saw two, goblins and one goblin boss, like, roaming around, like, patrolling there, like, trying to keep, an eye.
Kostadis Roussos: So I think we… it's hard to get past them without.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Breaking them down.
Kostadis Roussos: Just to be clear, you also notice that they are bored and inattentive, so you could probably surprise them.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Okay.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: So, looks like they are just relaxing.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Maybe it's a good time to be silent and attack them, give them a surprise attack.
Kostadis Roussos: Pip says, I'm always ready to attack a goblin! He pulls out his sword. Vera goes…
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: I need… I need all of you guys to be calm, silent.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, okay, so what do you want to do? Do you want to go around the top? Do you want to go through the little, the…
Kostadis Roussos: The briars?
Kostadis Roussos: What do you wanna do?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Yeah, I'm gonna… I want to go around the same point where I saw them from.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: So…
Kostadis Roussos: So, alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so you got… Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so everybody roll your stealth checks. Roll your stealth check.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: I rolled mine.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, you all, they are surprised.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, alright.
Kostadis Roussos: So, let's roll for Initiative.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Should I roll, or are you going to roll?
Kostadis Roussos: You need to roll for your guy.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Which one should I roll through the initiative? Okay, yeah, there is one initiative, yeah.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Now, that's intelligence.
Kostadis Roussos: initiative.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: No, I don't see… oh, yeah, yeah, yeah, okay, I found it, yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, 13.
Kostadis Roussos: And the golems…
Kostadis Roussos: 5.
Kostadis Roussos: Oops.
Kostadis Roussos: Very good, that one.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Goblin got a 21? Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, but they're surprised, so you get to go first. Xenobon.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Meh.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: I am going to…
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Start with a crossbow, because it's a surprise attack, and I cannot be close to them.
Kostadis Roussos: You can, if you want.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: I'll start with the crossbow.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: So the goblins have an armor class of 15.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Oh, so I'm a light armorer.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Right.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: So I roll a strength? No.
Kostadis Roussos: Now, you roll… if you go look, bring it… show me your character sheet, and I'll tell you what to click on.
Kostadis Roussos: I'm taking a share screen.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Where's your DNA? Okay, so,
Kostadis Roussos: We'll scroll down on the right side, scroll down.
Kostadis Roussos: Scroll to the left, so scroll to the le- swipe to the left.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, could you go scroll back up?
Kostadis Roussos: That's wrong with that alone.
Kostadis Roussos: Where are your attacks?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Come on, Sir, let me… Okay, I see it now, yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so you click on your shortbow.
Kostadis Roussos: So you see that, where that little… the arrow is on the left?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: You see all the way to the right, yeah, you click that and it rolls both your attack
Kostadis Roussos: And your damage in one go.
Kostadis Roussos: Ouch.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: 12 shortbow piercing, 8 Short Bow Sneak Attack, and 5.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, you rolled a natural one, which is an automatic miss.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: It was a mess? Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: No, is it?
Kostadis Roussos: What did you roll? Yes. You rolled a… yeah, you rolled a miss. You missed, alright.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Oh, shit.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, alright, pip…
Kostadis Roussos: So, alright. Where are we? Okay, so, zip goes, well, that sucks.
Kostadis Roussos: But he's like…
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: So, are they surprised, or, you know, are they alert right now?
Kostadis Roussos: Well, now there's a surprise, which is why you get a free round to attack.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Hmm.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: So… he rushes in.
Kostadis Roussos: He rushes in. Pip attacks this guy over here.
Kostadis Roussos: And this is, okay, that's not, that's not good.
Kostadis Roussos: Sister… Mela.
Kostadis Roussos: She casts a Sacred Flame.
Kostadis Roussos: What is it?
Kostadis Roussos: Gaza could blame.
Kostadis Roussos: And, okay, well, none of these attacks work, but fortunately, Vera says, well, that's what they have magic users for. And she's… she's coming from over there, she points her magic missiles.
Kostadis Roussos: through the briars. She comes over here, and she fires her magic missiles at the big boss. Actually, she fires one magic missile.
Kostadis Roussos: Not everybody, so they each take 3 points of damage.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Hmm.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: And then this guy takes another reprint to dodge.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so now… okay, this guy wakes up…
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, Vera, then after she does that, moves over here. Alright, so the goblin charges… Straight at… pip.
Kostadis Roussos: And swings is… Weapon.
Kostadis Roussos: And this is completely. Xenobon, you're up again.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Yes, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Now, this is a good time to use your daggers, your sword and your short dagger. Remember, you can attack twice with them.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Yes, yes, I have a dagger.
Kostadis Roussos: What did you roll?
Kostadis Roussos: You rolled a natural 20.
Kostadis Roussos: So you, you didn't just kill this guy, you, like, sent him… you… you… did you ever see the TV show, the game,
Kostadis Roussos: Final combat.
Kostadis Roussos: Mortal Kombat? Mortal Kombat?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Yes, yes, I've seen, KO.
Kostadis Roussos: Finish him. Finish him.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, Vera, after she had that success, is gonna say, actually, I'm gonna save my spells.
Kostadis Roussos: She's gonna fire a fire bolt.
Kostadis Roussos: It's a hit.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Yay.
Kostadis Roussos: Yep, she's ahead.
Kostadis Roussos: And it's, 5 points of damage.
Kostadis Roussos: And so the other goblin dies.
Kostadis Roussos: Alrighty.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so the other goblin…
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: We have a bar.
Kostadis Roussos: Right. And the boss sort of goes…
Kostadis Roussos: And, Farrah would not be here, she would, no. So, Sister Mela…
Kostadis Roussos: Comes charging at you, and swings at Pip.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Bring that pip?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, he does.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Oh, yeah, this guy, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, an irk swings at Pit, goes, and he misses completely.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Let me just make sure I got this guy.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, actually attacks twice with his Scimitar. He misses with the first attack.
Kostadis Roussos: And, let me just see what pit's armor class is?
Kostadis Roussos: And props armor clause is… Misses the second time as well. Alrighty.
Kostadis Roussos: So now it's Pip's turn.
Kostadis Roussos: Why don't you roll to hit? Roll a D20 and add 5 for pip.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: D20 and add sites, okay, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Yep, yep.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: So, slash R…
Kostadis Roussos: Detour.
Kostadis Roussos: plus 5.
Kostadis Roussos: Plus 4, actually, sorry, plus 4.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Added a file.
Kostadis Roussos: It doesn't matter, you missed. Alright. Sister Mela.
Kostadis Roussos: What does Sister Mela do?
Kostadis Roussos: She… roll a D20 to see if she's gonna try to hit him with her mace.
Kostadis Roussos: Right?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: It misses?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, roll a D20 and add 4.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, that's it, that, that you rolled… no.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: No, no, sorry. No, I think I did a… Yep.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, there we go. You said rolling 20 plus 4. Okay, that's a… that's a new way to roll a D20, alright. So you manage, she swings her mace and hits him, and does 6 points of damage.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Hmm.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: He's like, ough…
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, who is… Michael. Yeah, it's your turn.
Kostadis Roussos: Xenophon, I presume you're gonna try to walk up to him and, like, attack him twice with your daggers?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Yes, the dagger attack seems to be strong.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, this… alright, remember, short sword, and then dagger.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Oh, no.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: A dagger first.
Kostadis Roussos: That is a miss, alright?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: So, a short sword next.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Nice!
Kostadis Roussos: 9 points of damage.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Okay, another question, like, the previous thing was 13, right? The total damage from the damage?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Why did… did that work, or was it a miss?
Kostadis Roussos: You see the number next to dagger?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Hmm, yes?
Kostadis Roussos: That was what you rolled to hit.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: 20 is the number I rolled to hit.
Kostadis Roussos: So if you look at… if you… if you bring up… share your screen.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: this… number here.
Kostadis Roussos: Sorry. Yeah.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Yeah, the piercing damage.
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, this number here, the one over here.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Here, yes, yes, yes.
Kostadis Roussos: That, that number here.
Kostadis Roussos: That's your… that was the role you did to hit.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: His armor class is 17, so that's clearly below 7. 7 is clearly below 17.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Okay, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Right? So, you missed.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Oh, I see, okay. The short sport has an armor class of 20, like so.
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, no, no, so the way… no, no, so if you go back to this thing, what happened is, if you… if you look at this, right, over here, if you click on… click on the word… click on the short sword, like, put your mouse over the 20.
Kostadis Roussos: I know. Where do I have my red?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Yes, okay, yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: You see where it says.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: 15 plus 5.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, that means that you rolled a 15.
Kostadis Roussos: And you add 5 for your 2-hit bonus.
Kostadis Roussos: See this number here?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Yes, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Right? And that gives you a 20.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Right? Does that follow?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: So, what happened was you missed with the dagger and hit with a short sword.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Okay, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright? And so when you, when you click on this, like, just click… when you click on this, just click on it just for now, just so you can see how it works.
Kostadis Roussos: Click where I did a circle? No, no, no, not there.
Kostadis Roussos: That just… yeah. Okay, well, that… doesn't matter, it doesn't matter. That, when you roll over here, it just rolls to hit. If you roll where the… you see where the shortbow is? Right. Click there?
Kostadis Roussos: No, it's just… There.
Kostadis Roussos: Now, that is… then it says you rolled.
Kostadis Roussos: That's the damage you rolled. You see how it works, right?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Okay, okay, yep, yep.
Kostadis Roussos: Make sense?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Yes, yes, yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright. So, yeah, so the first attack was a miss, the second attack was a hit.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Okay.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Cool.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Alrighty.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, Vera of the Blue Candle will try to hit him with a firebolt again.
Kostadis Roussos: And she hits him.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Are we dead yet?
Kostadis Roussos: Let's see…
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, she kills him. He dies.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Right.
Kostadis Roussos: Anyway, what?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: trees are.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes. I'm assuming you're not, though, like, shouting at the top of your lungs to attract attention.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Of course, yeah.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: What's that?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: how to contain my exact…
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Let me see… alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Obligatory,
Kostadis Roussos: I don't know if you heard the victory music.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: I faintly hear it, some music, but…
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, probably.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Ignore.
Kostadis Roussos: Didn't work. Anyway, doesn't matter. Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so, you can look around to see if there's any treasure, which is always a good idea.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Oh, yes. Let's count this area for treasure, guys.
Kostadis Roussos: So you look over the dead bodies…
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Collect points.
Kostadis Roussos: Unfortunately… Unfortunately, they don't seem to have anything on them of any value.
Kostadis Roussos: Other than a… other than a javelin and a scimitar, so…
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Okay, I can take the weapons.
Kostadis Roussos: We're gonna take, the javelin?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: The javelin… can this guy handle javelin?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, he can. I know, I don't know if your guy can… I don't know if your guy can handle a javelin.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Right, how can I see the weapons? What we can…
Kostadis Roussos: If you, again, show your screen.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: That's inventory…
Kostadis Roussos: Yep, yep, click inventory.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Sean.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, so you see where it says, add equipment?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Click on that, and look, no.
Kostadis Roussos: And it just takes a second, and type over here.
Kostadis Roussos: Yep. Scimitar. S… a javelin, rather.
Kostadis Roussos: Scimitar, whatever. Alright, so if you click Add.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: And it's Pearl scimitar? Just the scimitar? Just the.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Equipment added. Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Right? Right?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Okay, I ordered both.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: I guess Pip should take a javelin, too.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: So, if the equipment is not, I mean, if the guy cannot handle the equipment, we cannot add that same here?
Kostadis Roussos: No, you can add it, but if you go to, like, to use it, you won't have a proficiency bonus.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Oh, I see, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: So as you go to Actions, go to Actions.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Yeah, this is the actions.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, you have to go to your equipment, go manage equipment?
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, and then you gotta look for…
Kostadis Roussos: Your javelin? Scimitar, click on the scimitar.
Kostadis Roussos: And where it says, equip.
Kostadis Roussos: Right? Now you're equipped with it.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: But I see the javelin as well.
Kostadis Roussos: So you go there, you equip it, Terrible.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: It works? Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, and then… well, hold on, I don't… I don't know how… this is where we're going to find out whether the PM agreed that this was a bug worth fixing. Click on the… go back to your actions.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, and
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, so, you don't have a… you're not… you don't have proficiency with that, which is why you only have plus one to hit.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Oh, with Javelin, yes, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Right?
Kostadis Roussos: If you had proficiency, you would have plus 5.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Okay, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: I think so. Anyway.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Shop.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, your proficiency is a plus 2, yes, so you do not have…
Kostadis Roussos: You are not proficient with it.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Okay, but I can still use it.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, but you use it a lot less effectively than other weapons.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: And is it, like, a one-time thing, Javelin? Because, you know.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, you can use it either as a ranged weapon, or a melee weapon.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so you can either throw it.
Kostadis Roussos: Or hold on, or hold onto it.
Kostadis Roussos: And stabby, stabby.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: And, and, I can… Once again, I'm sharing my screen.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Looks like I can increase the quantity here, like, you know…
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: It was saying 0.5 GP, if I increase the cost, it says the 4 pounds.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, I don't… okay, so here's something. There's this concept in Dungeons & Dragons called… encumbrance.
Kostadis Roussos: Which is, how many things you can carry.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Oh, okay, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: I don't play with it, because I don't believe… I believe that Dungeons & Dragons should not be about accounting. At the same time, if you're carrying 50,000 swords, I will say no.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so, like, no, I'm not gonna sit there and force you to count. Like, some people play with counting the number of arrows you shoot.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Oh, interesting. That's… okay.
Kostadis Roussos: I don't.
Kostadis Roussos: I, like, to me, the game is about the game, not about sitting there and playing resource management games. Other people, on the other hand, enjoy it and think that it adds to the game. I'm just telling you what I don't do.
Kostadis Roussos: So…
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Got it.
Kostadis Roussos: Got it? Yes.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Alrighty. Okay.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: We have, like, 5 more minutes.
Kostadis Roussos: Great, so we should add on another cliffhanger. Do you want to keep… like, let's go a little bit further into the cavern.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Yes, okay. Cliffhangers. I love cliffhangers, yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Xenophon, you probably want to sneak in to see what's going on.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Sneak in. Okay. Sneak, sneak roll.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, yes, they'll throw.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Yeah, still true, yes. Turn, still, still, still.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Stealth. Yes. What's the stealth.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Yeah. Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, 23.
Kostadis Roussos: What are… what race are you?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Halflick.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: You look…
Kostadis Roussos: You managed to walk over here and notice 3 wolves.
Kostadis Roussos: We have a few… you could keep walking if you want.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Okay, wait, do I see anything in the stealth, on the side, after the stealth roll? No?
Kostadis Roussos: No, yes, what you did was, nobody saw you, so the wolves didn't notice you.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: I see, okay, okay, so yeah, I'll keep walking and exploring until… because I have a stealth.
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, every time you move, you have to… every time you…
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: move, I have to roll a stealth.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, well, anytime somebody might notice you, you have to roll a stealth.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, roll another stealth roll.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Oh, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Or rather, you arrive over here, which way do you want to go?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Left side.
Kostadis Roussos: One sec.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, roll a stealth roll.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: The main passage from this cave mouth steeps
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, see if Special, alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: From this point on, you will need… you realize you will need either darkvision or a light source. If you're carrying a light source, it's gonna be kind of hard to walk stealthily, so you probably want to head back.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Okay, so I need a dark vision. How do I get it, like, collect somewhere?
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, darkvision is an ability of, of,
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Okay, ability. How do I gain that?
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, no, it's an ability of races.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Okay, so I have it already.
Kostadis Roussos: You either have it or you don't.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: I mean, okay, where can I check that?
Kostadis Roussos: And I think as a… halflings don't have darkvision.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: But, the good news is, Sister Mela, who's a dwarf, has it, and I think Vera, who is a tiefling, has it. So, that's the good news.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Okay, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: So, what?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Vera also has a candle, the blue light candle.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes. So, the problem with carrying a candle in the dark is that… Most of them.
Kostadis Roussos: It's kind of hard to be stealthy when you're carrying a bright light.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Of course, yes, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, men, we'll stop here.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Okay. Oh, oh, okay, I'm waiting for the cliffhanger, like, did I.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, you're…
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: anything? Did I sense anything? You know what I'm saying?
Kostadis Roussos: As you're… as you're standing there…
Kostadis Roussos: Mmm…
Kostadis Roussos: So, are you going up through here? Are you gonna try to go up there and just walk in the dark?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Yeah, I'm gonna stay there, like, my friends are behind.
Kostadis Roussos: Your friends aren't far back, fine, you're gonna have to go get them back.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Yes, yes.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Single.
Kostadis Roussos: As you stand there, this passage is choked with rubble and blocked by steep slide.
Kostadis Roussos: As you move up to it, just check out what's there.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: I legit thought that was a sound that you made.
Kostadis Roussos: You notice a giant, coiled, poisonous snake that…
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Right here. So as you go up there to check, what you suddenly hear is a hiss of a giant, poisonous snake.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so…
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: The snake. Oh, there, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: You can see the snake?
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: I can see a semicircular red color thing, I don't see the snake. I think the map is not clear for that part. Yes, I see the snake, yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, alright, cool. So, yes, there's a giant snake that, as… that you just sort of walk up, and you sort of look at it, and it kind of doesn't notice you.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, right in your face.
Kostadis Roussos: But thanks to your stealth, it hasn't noticed you yet.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Right, yes. So I slowly tiptoe back, and yeah, that's the cliffhanger, like, you know.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, yes, we stopped there. All right.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Alright, buddy.
Kostadis Roussos: Take care.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: I enjoyed this cost to this.
Kostadis Roussos: Me too, me too.
Nikhil Reddy Mettupally: Enjoy your weekend, thank you.
Kostadis Roussos: No problem, you too. Have a good one. Bye-bye.